한글자막 D (13myowncut@gmail.com)
고매하신 언론 관계자
여러분들을 위한
So, incorruptible tribunes
of the free press,
핀란드식 조찬이
마련되어 있습니다
please enjoy
this Finnish breakfast.
아시다시피 부통령 님께서
핀란드와 대단히 뜻깊은
As you know, the vice
president recently signed
소프트웨어 협약식을
맺은 바 있잖습니까
an historic software
agreement with Finland.
부통령 님 유럽 순방이야말로
노래 건으로 공로가 퇴색됐죠
Wasn't her trip to Europe
overshadowed by the song?
대놓고 유럽인들을
비아냥대시더만요
You know, the one where
she mocked Europeans?
비아냥이라니요
She wasn't
mocking Europeans.
- 다소 익살스러웠을 뿐이죠
- 익살이라?
- I would say the song was jesty.
- Jesty?
그보다 중요한 것은
But more importantly,
right now the vice president
부통령 님께서 국회의장 님과
회동 중이시라는 겁니다
is meeting with the House
Majority Leader Mary King.
국가 부채 조정에
획기적인 전기를 마련하시겠죠
And they are brokering
a debt reduction deal
재정 악재를 모면할 수
있으리라 봅니다
that's going to avert
a government shutdown.
우리 역사상 가장 위대한
부통령 자리에 등극하실 테죠
Selina Meyer's
becoming one of the most
effective American vice
presidents in history.
우즈베키스탄 인질 구조 작전
당시에 단연 일등 공신이셨죠
She was crucial in the freeing
of the Uzbekistan hostages.
- 그렇잖습니까?
- 그렇지
- Correct?
- Yes.
소프트웨어로 말씀드리ㅈ
The software--
인질 가운데 한 명이
스파이였단 사실도 아셨나요?
Did she know that one
of the hostages was a spy
그로 인해 나머지 세 학생이
사지로 몰린 격이죠
endangering the other
three students?
Um...
당시엔 인지하지 못 하셨지만
possibly not quite at the time.
그렇담 사건 해결에
결정적 역할을 수행하고 어쩌고
So all this stuff
she's been saying about
자평하셨던 부분들은
거짓말이 되겠군요
being a crucial part of
the military rescue is a lie.
어이쿠 진정하시게나, 리온
혈당이 떨어졌나 본데
Okay, slow down, Leon.
Is your blood sugar off?
패스트리랑 청어부터
좀 잡솨 봐
Have a pastry
or some herring, okay?
- 답변해 주시죠
- 부통령 님께서 정확히
- Answer the question.
- I don't know what she knew
언제, 어떤 정보를 입수하셨는가
알 수는 없다네
- or when she knew it, Leon.
- Mike, Mike.
종합하자면 스파이의 존재를
아셨던 동시에
Either she knew
that the student was a spy
그 사실을 부인함으로써
거짓말을 하셨든지 아님
and lied when she denied it,
스파이였단 사실까지는
파악 못 하셨지만
or she didn't know
that he was a spy,
군사 작전 감행에 대해 속속들이
파악했다고 거짓말한 것이로군요
but lied about knowing the
details of the military rescue.
또다시 '거짓말쟁이 설리나'
한 번 해보자는 겐가
This isn't
"Meyer the Liar" again.
그렇게 되고 말았군요
Well, it is now.
이번만큼은 누워서 떡 먹기
식으로 되지 않을 겁니다
This isn't going to be
a cakewalk, Selina.
결코 호락호락하지
않을 거라고요
- Oh.
- This one's the hard bargaining.
걱정도 팔자셔
협상하면 또 내가 전문이지
Don't you worry.
I know how to haggle.
어련하시겠어요
You betcha.
- 아이들은 잘 지내지?
- 그렇죠, 뭐
- How are your boys?
- They're great.
- 캐서린 양은요?
- 이제 21살이라네
- How's Catherine?
- She's 21.
- 다 컸네요
- 그렇잖아도 오늘이 파티야
- That's great.
- Yeah, we're having her party tonight.
- 얼마나 설레는지 몰라
- 오늘 밤이요?
- So I'm excited about that.
- Tonight?
부모라면 그저 제 자식들이
Yeah. You know, all you
ever want for these kids
- 건강하고 행복하기만을 빌잖나
- 물론이죠
- is to be happy and healthy.
- Right. You bet.
그리고 중동 쪽으로는
신경 끄고 살아주길 바라지
And stay out of
Middle East politics.
세 개 중에 두 개라도
들어주니 양호한 편이지
So two out of three ain't bad.
쿨하게 넘어가 주시다니
놀라울 따름입니다
I'm amazed you can
laugh about that.
달리 도리가 있겠나
웃어 넘겨야지, 뭐
Yes, that's what I do.
I'm laughing about it.
남자 친구가 있다죠?
She has that boyfriend.
- 결혼까지 이어질는지?
- 이만하면 됐고
- You think that's going to actually
lead to a marriage? - Should we get going...
- 할 일이 태산이잖나?
- 네, 그러시죠
- with this business at hand?
- Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
도대체 어떻게 돼 가는지
I wonder how
it's going in there.
조직 검사 결과라도
기다리는 기분이야
It's like waiting
for a biopsy result.
매리 대표 한 가닥하잖아
Mary's a player.
기절한 척 해서는 브라이언 얼을
눌러 버린 전력도 있다고
She did own Brian Earl in
negotiations by pretending to faint.
이따 밤에 캐서린 생일 파티
끝나고 따로 좀 볼까?
So after Catherine's birthday party
tonight, you want to grab a bite?
헬싱키 이야기도 마무리할 겸
전략 구상 해야지?
Talk about Helsinki,
strategize a little bit?
- 데이트 약속 있어
- 퍽이나
- I have a date for tonight.
- Yeah.
정말로?
Yeah?
- 누구랑?
- 에드
- Who is it?
- Ed.
뭐 하는 양반인데?
Ooh, and what does Ed do?
에드 웹스터, 기금 마련 행사를
주관하는 인물이지
Ed Webster is a fund-raiser
for the party
부통령 님 아래에서
일한 지가 5년이지
and he's worked for Selina
for the past five years.
묻는데 답해 주는 게
인지상정 아니겠니
- Sue.
- Cracked under the questioning.
부통령 님이랑 일하다니?
He's one of Selina's guys?
이 쪽 사람들이랑은
절대 만날 일 없다면서
You swore you were only
gonna date outside DC.
이 쪽 사람은 아냐
주로 보스턴에서 일하니까
He's not in DC.
He works in Boston.
우리 어머닌 로마 살지도 않는데
카톨릭 신자다, 어떻게 생각해?
Well, my mom doesn't live in Rome,
but she's still a fucking Catholic.
- Are you getting worked up, Danny?
- Shut the fuck up, Gary.
- 빡치는 거야, 대니?
- 시발 입 닥쳐
응원해 주다니
이렇게 고마울 데가
I'm so happy you're
happy for me, Dan.
어떻게, 케익 선물이라도 주랴?
Oh, what do you want,
a fucking cake?
봐, 기뻐 미치겠다
Look, I can be happy.
See?
됐지
There you go.
이 쪽에서 삭감할 구석은
실업 보험밖에 없군요
The only real cut here
is unemployment insurance.
매리, 대통령께서 결코
승낙하지 않으실 거야
Mary, POTUS is not
gonna make any cuts
to unemployment insurance
and you know that.
협상이 뭐 어떤 건지
한 말씀 올려 드릴까요?
Do I need to explain to you
how haggling works?
국립 보건원으로 가는 10%를
줄이면 만족하겠나?
How about a 10% cut
to NIH, okay?
- 20%는 되어야죠
- 안 될 소리야
- I need 20.
- I can't do those numbers.
씨알도 안 먹힐 소리지
That's not gonna work.
- 갓 블레스 유
- 감사합니다
- God bless you.
- Thank you.
그럼 역시 실업 보험 삭감
외에는 별수 없군요
Then the only obvious solution
is unemployment insurance.
아니, 말했잖아
그럴 수 없다고
No, I told you. I can't do that.
무슨 꿍꿍인가?
What are you doing?
무슨 말씀이신지?
What?
시간이라도 벌 요량이야?
You stalling for time?
휴지 좀 갖다 주겠네
Let me get you a Kleenex, yeah?
괜찮습니다
세 번이면 멎더라고요
I think it's over. Sneezes
always come in threes.
- 모르셨어요?
- 그래? 그런가?
- Have you ever noticed that?
- Really? Is that so?
오우, 네 번째 재채기로군
Oh, well, that was a fourth.
내 쪽에서 수 세기에 관해
한 말씀 올릴 차례인가?
So maybe I need to tell you about
how counting works, right?
좋아
- All right.
- Okay.
- 자금을 좀 확보ㅎ...
- 뭐라고?
- We can raise fees...
- The what?
- 아메리카 원주민 복ㅈㅣ...
- 응? 기절할 것 같다고?
- ...on Indian Health Services.
- Hmm? You gonna faint?
아닙니다
짓궂기도 하셔라
I'm not--
oh, very funny.
- 물 마실래?
- 네
- Do you want water?
- Yes.
직접 가져다 주지
I'll get you some water.
- 잠깐만 기다리라고
- 알겠습니다
- I'm gonna get you water.
- Okay.
- 좀 어떠세요?
- 강경하게 나가시는군요?
- How's it going, ma'am?
- Wow, you're really hardballing her, huh?
기침한답시고 토악질이라도
할 기세로 저러고 있다
No, she's pretending
to cough herself inside out.
안에 물 한 잔 부탁할게
Could you get her
some water, please?
어쩌자는 건지
I don't know what--
어머, 세상에
매리, 괜찮은 거야?
Ooh! Oh, my God!
Mary, are you all right?
알레르기 반응인가 봐요
I think I'm having
an allergic reaction.
- 무슨 알레르기길래?
- 여기 혹시 고양이 털 날리나요?
- What are you allergic to?
- Is there cat hair?
- 제가 고양이를 길러요
- 아, 개리가 키워
- I have cats.
- Oh, Gary has cats.
잠깐만, 개리 x 3
물은 주고 가야지
Wait, Gary, Gary, Gary.
We need the water.
- 여깄어
- 이 모헤어 때문일까요?
Yeah, there you go.
Is it this mohair?
그럴 수도 있겠다
모헤어 때문이야?
- It might be the mohair.
- Do you think?
- 아닐 거래
- 견과류 알레르기이십니까?
- No, she's been here--
- The nuts? Is it the nuts?
집어먹은 적 있나?
아니라고?
- Did you eat nuts? No?
- Mm-mmm.
- 혹시 꽃가루 알레르기이십니까?
- 뭣이라?
- Is it the flowers?
- What?
캐서린 생일이라 미리
준비해 놨었거든요
The ones I got
for Catherine's birthday.
오, 하나님
저 시발 것들이었어
Oh, Christ!
Those fuckers!
- 바로 저거라고
- 제길, 죄송합니다
- That's it.
- Shit, okay. All right, sorry.
- 흐미
- 개리, 무꽃 상태로 만들어
- Oh, God.
- Gary, deflower the room.
저런 소리 들으며
살 줄은 몰랐겠지
There's a sentence I bet you
thought you'd never hear.
네 시간이나 더 버티고
앉았을 자신이 없어요
I'm not good
for another four hours.
오늘 밤에 다시
뵙도록 하죠
Selina, we've got to take
this up tonight.
매리, 딸아이 생일이라니까
Mary, I've got my
daughter's 21st birthday.
- 가지 마셔요
- 어떻게 안 갈 수가 있어
- Don't go.
- I can't not go to her--
자네 같음 자네 아들
동성 결혼식 안 가고 배기겠나?
Would you miss your son's
Civil Union ceremony?
- 안 갔는데요
- 이런
- I did.
- Oh.
그럼 캐서린 파티장으로 오게
Well, then, you have to come to Catherine's.
- 오늘 밤에 담판을 짓자고
- 네, 이따 봬요
- We've got to finish this tonight.
- Yes, we do, tonight.
그러라고
하나 더 달고 오든지
Come. You can bring a plus one.
좆만한 산소 탱크라도
옆에 끼고 기어오라고
Stick a coat and tie
on a fucking oxygen tank.
마이크, 리온 웨스트가 자꾸
제 앞으로 연락하더군요
Mike, Leon West
called my line twice.
또 휴대폰 분실한 거예요?
Did you lose your phone again?
그건 아닌데 리온이 자꾸
스파이 건에 대해서 걸고 넘어지잖아
No, Leon's a little skeptical
about the whole spy thing
다시 '거짓말쟁이 설리나'로
선동하려는 놈도 있고
and some dumbass is
resurrecting Meyer the Liar.
거짓말쟁이(Liar)랑 내 이름이
라임 좀 맞기로서니?
Ugh, just because my last
name rhymes with liar.
어찌나 감사한지, 원
'강간범' 설리나라든가
How lucky am I that
I'm not Selina Mapist
'소아성애자' 설리나
아닌 게 어디야
or Selina Medophile?
매리 의장 보니까 고래 토사물에서
건져 올려진 모양새더군요
I just saw Mary King. Looked like
she's been thrown up by a whale.
알레르기 반응 때문에 그래
Yeah, she had
an allergy attack.
협상은 잘 됐습니까?
성사시켰다고 해 주십시오
So did you do the deal?
Tell me you did the deal.
밤에 마저 얘기하려고
캐서린 파티에 올 거야
I'm gonna finish it tonight. She's
coming to Catherine's birthday party.
얼라리, 자정 안으로
끝장을 보지 못 하면
Jesus. You know, if we don't
get this done by midnight,
싸그리 못난이 자매로 변신해서
늑대 새끼들한테 잡아먹힐걸요
we're all gonna turn into ugly
sisters and get eaten by wolves
거 왜, 그런 이야기로
빌어먹을 동화도 있잖습니까
or whatever the fuck happens
at the end of that story.
소닉 붐이 일겠습니다요
부통령 님
Sonic boom in the room.
Ma'am.
- 안 돼
- 아, 넵
- No.
- Oh, okay.
부채 조정 협상
진행 과정에 대해
Well, POTUS wanted me
to come down here
and peep the skinny
on the debt negotiations.
정찰해 보라는 대통령 님의
명으로 왔습니다만
화기엄금 되시겠다
Okay, that's a fire hazard,
so let's just...
개리, 대통령 님께서 친히
나로 하여금...
Gary, I have been sent here
from the president.
대통령 님께서는 벌써
엄청난 압박에 시달리십니다
Okay, so the president's already
going through a lot of pressure
인질 건으로 구라치고
법석을 떨어 놔서
about this hostage
lying bullshit.
- 압박에 시달리신다?
- 네
- He's under pressure?
- Yes.
- 나야말로 쪼들린다고
- 선택지를 읊어드리죠
- I'm under pressure.
- Well, you do have a choice.
인질 구조작전에 개입한 바
없다고 선을 그으시는 겁니다
You could say you were out of the
loop for the hostage rescue,
단, 무능력해 뵈겠죠
혹은 적극 개입했다 밝히시든지요
which would make you look clueless, or
you could say you were in the loop,
물론 기만적으로
비칠 수밖에 없죠
which would make
you look devious.
어느 쪽이든 시발 좀
잠잠해져야 살지 않겠습니까
Either way, just blur
the fuck out of it.
Uh-huh.
- 이런, 니미
- 부통령 님
- Oh, fuck.
- Ma'am.
도와드릴 만한 ㄱ
Anything that I should--
에이미, 에드 웹스터 와 있어
Amy, Ed Webster
is here to see you.
긴장한 것 같더라
목소리가 끈적거린달까
I think he's nervous.
His voice sounded clammy.
그래, 괜찮아
괜찮고 말고
Oh, okay. That's good.
That's good.
혼이 쏙 빠진 것 같다?
Look at you all flustered.
드디어 섹스를 하겠구나
이런 경사스런 날이
It's good that
you'll have sex soon.
Okay, guys, we need
to prep two press releases
파티에서 매리 킹과의
회동이 끝나면 배포할
언론 보도 자료 두 건을
미리 준비해야겠어
for the end of the Mary King
talks at the party tonight.
우선 버전 1이야
Okay, version one--
Selina Meyer
설리나가 재정 교착 상태를
타개하고 미국을 구하다
ends fiscal deadlock,
saves America.
버전 2, 매리 킹이
평화의 담뱃대를 쌔벼서는
Version two-- Mary King
steals peace pipe,
두 동강을 내더니
똥칠을 해제끼더라
breaks it in half,
shits all over it.
부통령 님, 전 부군께서
전화하셨습니다
Ma'am, your ex-husband
just called.
직접 캐서린 양을
태워주겠다고 하시는군요
He says that he wants
to pick up Catherine.
안 돼, 이미 차 준비시켜 놨는걸
No, I have a car picking her up already.
I arranged that.
약아빠진 좆같은 근성
어디 안 갔네
He is such a conniving,
grabby prick.
- 몸에 밴 거지?
- 놀라울 따름이죠
- Is it typical or what?
- Unbelievable.
- 분명 잘못된 겁니다
- 미워 죽겠다니까요
- Just wrong.
- I hate him so much.
죄송합니다만
왜 그러시는 거죠?
Sorry, can I ask why?
이해하기 쉬운 예를
하나 들어줄까
This'll
explain it perfectly.
때는 2년 전
밸런타인 데이였어
Valentine's Day
a couple years ago,
나한테 까만색 포르쉐를
주더라니까
- he gave me a black Porsche...
- Oh.
캐서린 신탁 자금을 깨서
마련한 거였지
that he bought with
Catherine's trust fund money.
그러니 뭐랄까, 되로 먹이고
말로 또 먹이는 새끼라니까
- Oh. - I mean, he just fluffs ya,
and then he fucks ya.
Yeah.
Well, speaking of...
기왕 말문 여신 김에...
그래, 맞아
그것도 적절한 사례지
Oh, yeah,
that's a perfect example.
자, 들어 봐
Here you go.
So, he took me
한 번은 프랑스 앙티브로
데려가더라고
to Cap d'Antibes for the night.
폭풍ㅅㅅ를 치르셨던
날이기도 하지
Yeah, they had
crazy intercourse.
그리고선 하는 말이 뭐냐면
Only after which he told me
글쎄 우리 별장을
팔아 먹었다는 거 있지
that he sold our second home.
쇠망치 들고 설치는
밸리 댄서가 따로 없다니까
Yeah, yeah. He's like a
belly dancer with a hammer.
많이 속상하셨겠어요
That would hurt.
그치만 말야
앤디 따위 신경 안 써
You know what?
I'm not worried about Andy
완전 없는 인간
취급할 거니까
because I'm gonna
completely obliterate him
존나 침착하고도
쌔끈하게 말이지
with my fucking poise
and sophistication.
이해들 했지?
You know what I mean?
- 어쩜, 너도 들었지?
- 응, 당연하지
- God, did you hear that?
- Yeah, yeah.
앤디라고 부르셨어
앤드류도 아니고
She's calling him Andy
instead of Andrew.
- 시작됐어
- 뭐가?
- It's starting.
- What?
앤디가 떴다 하면 여지없이
Every time Andy's on the scene,
- 뭐랄까 제대로...
- 바람이 드신다고
- she gets all...
- Giddy.
이렇게 막 처참하게
깔깔거리셔
She's--
this terrible laugh.
- 이렇게 말야
- 바로 이거지
- She's like...
- Yeah, exactly.
- 요렇게 막
- 옳소, 옳소
- With a...
- Yeah. Yeah. Mm-hmm.
- 증오한다고 하셨는데
- 물론이지
- She just said that she hates him.
- She does.
그런데도 그 분 주위에서
어슬렁거리시다 보면
But every time
she gets around him...
진짜 괴상해, 양치기 인형 위에
올라탄 고양이 같아지신다고
It's so weird. It's like
a cat on a hot tin dog.
- 개리
- 네?
- Gary.
- Yeah?
- 빨간 거 기억나지?
- 네
- You know my red thing?
- Yeah.
그 정도 노출이면 족하겠지?
Do you think that
it shows enough skin?
- 네
- 좋아
- Yeah.
- Okay.
재정 건전성을 역설한 역사상
가장 핫한 여인네가 되고 말 거야
I'm gonna be the sexiest woman
to ever exude fiscal prudence.
잘 들어 둬, 존나 구현하기에
빡센 룩이니까
And you know what? That's a very
fucking tough look to pull off.
- 그렇지 않겠어?
- 브라 착용은 불가능한 의상인데요
- Don't you think?
- Okay, you can't wear a bra with that one.
어, 알아
Yeah, I know.
- 에이미
- 왔구나
- Amy.
- Hey.
에드, 잘 왔ㅇ
- Hey, Ed. How are--
파티 갈 준비는 된 거지?
So you all ready
for the party?
미리 경고할게
파티하면 또 나니까
Um, fair warning,
I party pretty hard.
나의 댄스를 잘 봐두라고
You should see me dance.
나조차도 통제할 수 없어
- I can't be controlled.
- Oh.
골반 튕기기가
주를 이루는데
- I do a lot of pelvic thrusts.
- Oh.
공간을 많이
잡아먹는 편은 아냐
Just very localized dancing.
아주 자그마한 반경이지
Very small orbits.
13살 이후로 줄곧
파티라면 결딴을 내고 다녔어
I've been wrecking parties
since I was 13.
바르미츠바에 행차한
헌터 S. 톰슨이 따로 없었지
I was like the Hunter S.
Thompson of bar mitzvahs.
부통령 님 안에 계셔?
Hey, is the vice
president here?
괜히 기웃대는 걸로
보이긴 싫어
I didn't want it to seem
like I was lurking.
아, 전혀 안 그래
Yeah, yeah.
No, you're not.
보시면 반가워하실 게 분명해
She'll be thrilled
to see you again.
부통령 님
Madam Vice President.
아... 반갑습니다?
Uh... hello?
- 안녕하십니까
- 안녕하신가
- Hi.
에드입니다
- Uh...
- Ed.
- 에드 아시죠
- 그럼
- You know Ed.
- Yeah.
아, 맞아!
그랬었지!
Oh, yes! Oh, yes, of course.
Oh, no.
그, 그, 그
본 적 있잖아
We-- we-- we--
we-- we met in...
아이다호 어드메였지
in Bumfuck, Idaho,
I think it was.
- D.C.에서 뵀죠
- 응, 그러니까
- DC.
- Yes, yes.
D.C.를 농담 삼아
그렇게 부르곤 한다네
That's what I like
to call DC as a joke.
옿
Oh.
잘 왔네, 잘 왔어
- Well...
- Great. Great.
- 이따 뵙겠습니다
- 그래
- I'll see you again soon, ma'am.
- Okay.
- 거기서 보자
- 응, 갈게
- We're meeting there, yeah? Okay.
- Right. Bye.
이보게, 못 알아보셨다고
속상해 말라고
Hey, buddy, don't worry that
she didn't remember you, okay?
그저 자네 존재감이
미미했을 뿐이니까
It's only 'cause
you're a nonentity.
- 누구였지?
- 그게, 에드 웹스터라고
- Who is he?
- That was-- that's Ed Webster.
제 파트너인데, 부통령 님
보스턴 사무실을 맡고 있어요
He's my date for tonight. He
runs your PAC's Boston office.
연고도 아주 풍부해요
- Oh.
- He's really connected.
로비스트였다가
기금 모금 활동도 하고
Lobbyist turned fundraiser.
버스 정류장에서 바구니 들고
설치는 그 모금은 아닐 테지?
Not the guy at a bus station
with a bucket, right?
앤드류랑 맞장 뜰
준비는 끝났어
Okay, I am ready
to take on Andrew.
기분 전환부터 해 볼까나
환희의 알약으로
I need my happy pills,
a little bit of joy.
어떠니?
맘에 들어?
So what do you think?
Do you like it?
- 네, 그게... 믿기지가 않네요
- 그치?
- Yeah, it's-- it's unreal, Mom.
- Right?
너희 친구들 사이에서
역사적인 날로 기억되겠지?
I mean, don't you think
that you and your friends
would call this whole
thing an epic succeed?
그 비슷하겠네요
Something like that, yeah.
너희 아빠 봐라
변함없는 짓거리 중이구나
Ah, there's your dad
doing that thing that he does.
손님들이랑 안부 주고받는 거요?
Pleasantly talking
to other people?
어떤 짓거린지 알잖니
You know what he does.
사람마다 뭐 한 가지씩
외워 놨다가 써먹는 거
He remembers one little thing
about each person.
로렌스, 반갑네
마라톤 하는 건 여전하지?
Lawrence, nice to see you.
You still running marathons?
젖꼭지 안 쓸리고
보전해서 다행이야
- Yes, sir. - Right, surprised
you still got any nipples left.
아이고 제니, 반가워
And Jenny.
Nice to see you.
그 때 기억나지, 왜
Remember that one time
when you said
자기가 트와일라잇에 푹 빠졌댔는데
난 무슨 해질녘 말하는 줄 알고
you were way into "Twilight" and I
thought you meant the time of day?
그치만 그 맘때쯤 특히
차조심 하긴 해야 돼
It really is the most
dangerous time for traffic, though.
그럼, 재밌게 놀다 가게
Please, enjoy yourselves.
- 앤드류?
- 매리
- Andrew?
- Mary.
- 잘 지냈어요?
- 무척 반갑군요, 의원 님
- How are you?
- Wonderful to see you, Congresswoman.
엄마, 내 생일 파티에
국회의장을 초대했어요?
Mom, you've invited the House
Majority Leader to my birthday party?
얘야, 예산을 무려
천 억이나 삭감해야 한다고
Yeah, sweetheart,
it's the 100 billion cutoff.
- 들어는 봤니?
- 그야 들어 봤죠
- You've heard about that?
- Of course I've heard about that.
그러니 지금 우린 전세계적
위기 상황을 극복 중이란다
Okay, so we are fixing the
biggest problem facing the world
바로 여기, 바로 지금
다름 아닌 네 생파에서
right here, right now
at your party.
꽤나 쌈박하지
그렇지 않니?
So that's kind of cool,
don't you think?
- 안녕하세요
- 아, 안녕
- Hello.
- Oh, hi.
여기 샴페인 좀 드세요
I got you a glass of champagne.
고마워, 라힘
자네 음주해도 되나?
Thank you, Rahim.
You drink alcohol?
- 물론입니다
- 이란인들은 놀랄 구석이 많구먼
- Yes, ma'am.
- Oh, you Iranians are full of surprises.
- 건배
- %^$@$^
- Cheers.
- Salamati.
- 방금 뭐였어요?
- 난들 아나
- What did he just say?
- I don't know.
횡설수설 하는데
알아먹을 수가 있어야지
Some gibberish.
I can't understand him.
자기, 사람들한테 인사 마쳤음
Hey, baby, once you've
said hello to everyone,
우리도 좀 놀고 즐겨야지?
do you want to go clubbing?
응, 여기만 아니라면
Yeah.
Anywhere but here.
벤, 자네가 어쩐 일이야?
Ben, what are you doing here?
- 대통령 님께 보고 올렸습니다
- 그랬더니?
- I spoke to POTUS.
- Yeah?
실업 급여 삭감도
오케이 하셨어요
And he said okay on the cut
to unemployment benefits.
모든 게 해결됐다고요
All the other deals are done.
그러니 이 정도 해두고
파티나 땡기십시다
So come on, let's get this tied up
so we can get this party started.
응, 근데 무슨 짓이지?
Yeah, I--
what did you do?
분신술이라도 부린 겐가?
You plus 10'd yourself here?
회동을 성사시키기 위해
자료 분석관들을 데려왔습죠
Number crunchers to help
you finish the deal.
저기 한 명은 운전수예요
- Yeah.
- And one of them is a designated driver
제가 오늘 개꽐라 될 예정이라
because I am going
to get fucked up.
근사한데요
걸작이 따로 없군요
You look so good,
you're like a work of art.
덕분에 다른 잡것들이
개똥만도 못해 보여요
You make this stuff
look like shit.
그대에 비하면 저 모네 그림은
쓰레기에 불과하달까
Compared to you, that
Monet is a piece of shit.
- 시작해 볼까요?
- 5분만 기다려
- Selina, are you ready?
- Give me five minutes.
앤드류랑 할 말이 있어서
I just got to go
talk to Andrew, okay?
전 남편이요?
3분 드릴게요
The ex?
Three minutes.
뭐야, 벌써부터 밀당이야?
그렇담 4분을 제안하지
What, are you negotiating already?
I'll give you four.
제가 3분 내로 모셔오겠습니다
- I'll cut her off at three, okay?
- Mm-hmm.
- 안녕, 설리나
- 안녕, 앤드류
- Hi, Selina.
- Hi, Andrew.
동네방네 인사치레 날리고
돌아다니는 거 보니 기쁘다
It's nice to see you greeting
everybody here at the party
꼭 네 잔칫날 같고 좋아
as if it was your own
fabulous party.
- 한 방 먹이려고?
- 그럴지도
- Are you fucking with me?
- I might be.
그렇군
All right.
- 아주 멋져 보여
- 대단히 감사해
- You look wonderful.
- Thank you very much.
많이 그슬렸네
무슨 일 있었어?
You're very tanned.
What is that?
케이먼 제도에 다녀왔어
스쿠버 다이빙 시작했거든
Grand Cayman. I've been
starting to scuba dive.
마법 같은 광경이 펼쳐진다고
- Oh.
- Magical to be down there.
산호초 하며 물고기들이라니
- Uh-huh.
- With the coral and the fish.
인어들도 좀 주물럭거리고
Feeling up all the mermaids.
그게 싫었다면
좀 더 갖춰 입었어야지
They should cover up if they don't want it.
꼬이는 게 싫으면
꽁꽁 싸매고 다녀야 한다고
If they don't want action,
they shouldn't advertise.
- Oh, gosh.
- Our little Catherine.
- 아이고 어쩌누
- 우리 꼬맹이 캐서린
아직도 애기라니까
- She's still cute.
Mm-hmm.
신혼 때 살았던
아파트 기억나?
Remember that first apartment?
응, 기억나고 말고
Yeah, I do remember
that apartment.
그 정도면 훌륭한 편이었다고
That was a nice
apartment, actually.
- 그랬었지
- 맞아
- It was.
- Yeah.
이거 뭐야?
청혼이라도 하려고?
What are you doing?
Are you gonna propose?
그에 대한 답은?
What would your answer be?
내 대답은 말야
지져스 퍼킹 하나니ㅁ
My answer would
be Jesus fucking Christ.
부통령 님, 킹 의원께서
애타게 기다리십니다
Uh, ma'am. Mary King is very
anxious to speak with you.
- 아, 그랬지
- 캐서린 생일 파티인데?
- Oh, right. Right.
- At Catherine's birthday?
그게, 재정 악재
국면 전환이 시급해서
Well, I'm trying to keep the
government from shutting down.
- 아, 건투를 빌어
- 아무렴 건투해야지
- Well, get on it.
- I'm getting on it.
네, 가시죠
Yeah, okay.
방금 봤어?
내 손바닥 위에 있다니까
Did you see that? I had him
in the palm of my hand.
엄밀히 말씀드리자면, 부통령 님
손바닥을 쥐락펴락하시던걸요
Well, technically, ma'am, he had
the palm of your hand in his hand.
각별히 조심하세요, 자기
- Oh.
- You need to be really careful, sweetie.
개리, 방금 날
'자기'라고 불렀잖아
Gary, you just
called me sweetie.
어머, 이럴 수가!
죄송합니다
Oh, my God!
I'm sorry.
- 데이나한테 하던 습관 때문에
- 걔한테 '부통령 님'이라고 부른 적은?
- That's what I call Dana.
- Did you ever call Dana ma'am?
한 번 그랬었는데
아주 민망했어요
I did once and it was awful.
내가 지금 술이 많이 됐음
키스도 해줬을 거야?
If I were drunk right now,
would you kiss me?
- 네
- 안 돼 개리, 농담이라고!
- Yeah.
- No, Gary, I'm kidding.
그럴 줄 알았어요
- Right.
- Yeah.
한 잔 걸쳐야겠다
I'm gonna get a drink.
- 매리
- 좋았어!
- Mary.
- Okay!
이제부터 지대로
달리기 시작하는 거다!
It's time to drop
a party bomb up in here.
생일 축하한다, 캐서린!
Happy 21st birthday, Catherine!
중점 긴축 분야를
선정하는 건 어떻겠나?
I want to talk to you
about targeted base closings.
제 지역구에 누만 끼치지
않는다면요
Not if it upsets my district.
좆 가리고 아웅하기 말이지?
Something sex my dick trick?
- 방금 좆이라 하셨어요?
- 자네가 좆 가리고 아웅 식이길래
- Did you say dick?
- Sex your dick trick.
I don't understand
what you just said.
도통 알아먹을 수가 없군요
웃자고 해본 소리야
여기서 나가자
It was funny.
We got to get out of here.
- 네, 어디로요?
- 글쎄, 찾아 봐야지
- All right. Where?
- I don't know. We'll find someplace.
갤러리에 계시니
더욱 돋보이는군요
You know, you look great
in an art gallery
존재 자체가 하나의
걸작이라 그런가요
'cause you kind of are
a work of art.
당장에라도 벽에 못질해
두고 싶은 미모이십니다
I mean, I know I'd like to
nail you up against a wall.
아니, 너무 당연한가요
새삼 얘기해 봤습니다
No, that was knowing.
I was being knowing.
It looks like we're gonna
be able to move
실업 급여 쪽으로
논의해 볼까
on unemployment.
- 실업 급여를요?
- 응
- Unemployment benefits?
- Yes.
- 논의의 여지가?
- 있지 그럼
- On the table?
- Yeah.
OSHA 예산을 25에서 17로
낮출 것을 건의합니다
Okay, I'm authorized to come
down on OSHA from 25 to 17.
안 돼, 한 자릿수로
합의 보지
No, I need a single digit.
그렇게는 불가능합니다만
I can't give you a single digit.
다른 방면에서 메꿔야 할 텐데
역부족인 거 아시잖아요
We'd have to make it up elsewhere
and you know you can't do that.
충분히 가능하리라 믿어
잠시만 있어 봐
And we are gonna make it up elsewhere.
Hang on just a second.
이봐, 아가씨들
좀 조용히 해주겠나?
Hey, gals. Gals, you need
to keep it down, okay?
이 쪽은 지금 심각한 대화
중이라 말이야
There are other people in here
trying to have a conversation.
제 남친 번호를 따갔다고요!
But she took
my boyfriend's number!
- 이런, 시상에
- 걔가 쥐어 주더라니까!
- Oh, my God.
- He gave it to me!
부통령 님은 제게 어떤
수치도 안 쥐어 주시는군요
You haven't given me a number
on unemployment benefits.
- 내가 말하는 수치는 0.4%야
- 0.4%라고요?
- My number's gonna be .4%.
- .4?
- 그렇대도
- 그렇게는...
- Yeah.
- I can't--
여기선 무리겠어, 나가세
- I can't do this. Let's go.
- No.
이런 난리통에서
산수를 할 수야 없죠
I can't do math
with this kind of noise.
- 십대 여자애들은 질색이야
- 십대 시절 없으셨어요?
- I cannot stand teenage girls.
- Were you ever one?
- 없었다 마다
- 이하동문입니다
- Never.
- Me neither.
에이미와 에드라고 하지요~
부통령 님 밑에서 일한답니다~
Amy and Ed work for the VP,
~K I S S I N G~
K-I-S-S-I-N-G.
- 꺼져 주세요, 마이크
- 그러지
- Fuck off, Mike.
- Sure.
오늘 부통령 님
대박 화끈하시더라
Hey, the veep looks
smoking tonight.
보드카를 어느 정도
들이키면 가능할까?
I wonder how much vodka
we'd need to have
로빈슨 부인 타임을
가지려면 말이야
to have a little
Mrs. Robinson moment.
이루 말할 수 없이
무례한 언사군
That is extremely
disrespectful.
무슨 소리야?
What are you talking about?
이보다 더 수준 높은
찬사란 있을 수가 없구만
That's like the highest
compliment you can give somebody.
그건 그렇고
Oh, by the way,
너희 둘이 꽁냥댐으로써
댄이 엿먹다니 행복하구나
I love how much you guys being
together is fucking with Dan.
에이미랑 댄이 그렇고 그랬거든
혹시 몰랐나 해서
Amy and Dan used to date, FYI.
과거지사를 캐내 주다니
어찌나 고마운지 몰라
Yeah, thanks for
the backgrounding, Jonah.
이로써 다시 혼자가 된 거야?
Does that mean you're
back on the market?
내가 두 눈 시퍼렇게
뜨고 있는데 집적대?
I'm sorry, are you hitting
on my date during my date?
약이라도 했어?
Are you on meds?
항생제 조금
똘똘하게 지내려고
Yeah, antibiotics.
Just keeping fresh.
내 정신머리는 멀쩡해
I'm not mentally ill
그게 궁금한 거라면
if that's what you're implying.
안녕하십니까?
반가워요
Uh, hello? Hi.
다들 반갑습니다
Hi, everyone.
I just wanted to say
우리 이쁜 딸내미에 관해
몇 마디 하겠습니다
a couple of words
to my awesome daughter.
잠시 이 자리를 빌어
한 말씀 드리자면
You know, I wanted
to pause and just say
that I think
at times like these
지금처럼 가족, 친구들을
만나는 게 얼마나 기쁜 일인지요
it is great to see
family and friends
그들의 목소리에
귀를 기울일 수 있고요
and to hear family and friends.
이야기를 주고 받고
담소를 나눌 수도 있잖아요
To be able to talk
and to listen
and to speak and to be heard.
그리고 이따금씩 시간을
가지는 것도 중요하겠죠
And I think sometimes
we need to just take time.
그리 길지 않더라도
한 10분 정도 말예요
Not long at all.
I mean, maybe 10 minutes or--
아니다, 15분도 괜찮겠군요
okay, or maybe 15 is also good.
건설적인 대화의 시간을
가질 것을 제의하는 바입니다
I'm gonna suggest that we have a
little constructive talking time.
뭐랄까 잔잔한 음악
좀 깔 수 없을까요?
So do you have any sort
of chillaxing kind of music?
주욱 틀어 놓으세요
And then you keep that playing until--
언제까지 트냐면, 날 봐요
내가 신호할 때까지
only until-- look at me--
I give you a signal.
- 무턱대고 끄면 안 돼요
- 알겠습니다
- Not before.
- Sure.
아, 생일 축하해
Ooh, and happy birthday,
캐서린!
Catherine!
- 돌입해 볼까나
- 실업 급여로 1%를 책정한다면
- All right. - If you can give me 1%
on unemployment benefits...
국립보건원 쪽으로
10% 돌릴 수 있습니다
- Yeah.
- I can go 10 on NIH,
농업 지원금 8% 삭감하고요
eight off
agricultural subsidies.
전년도 예산안에 기초했습니다
The baseline is your budget
proposal from last year.
- 그렇구나
- 합계가 나오잖습니까?
- Right. Okay.
- Okay, those numbers add up?
- 최종 10이겠구먼
- 12죠
- I make it 10.
- 12.
12라니 어떻게?
12? How'd you get that?
- 에너지 분야도 있잖아요
- 그랬지, 참
- You're forgetting energy.
- Of course.
살펴 보시게
이 정도에서 합의 볼까?
Check this out, then.
Do we have a deal?
네, 좋습니다
Okay, yeah, great.
드디어 성사됐군요
- Yeah, we have a deal.
- Yeah!
죽을 뻔했지만
해내고야 말았어요
- It nearly killed me, but we have a deal.
- Put 'er there.
- 이제 된 거야
- 축하드립니다
- Put 'er there.
- Congratulations.
이럴 수도 있구만
- I can't believe it.
- Isn't that--
놀라워, 매리
너무 잘 됐다
I can't believe it, Mary.
That's so great.
그럼 당 지도부 측에
알리러 가야겠습니다
It's good. Now I have
to sell it to my caucus
자정이 지나 호박으로
변해 버리기 전에요
- before I turn into a pumpkin.
- You'll do it.
어히휴
Yeah.
Oh, God.
얼씨구, 21살이란
원래 이렇게 재빠른 거야?
Jesus, 21-year-olds
move fast.
그러니까요
누가 아니랍니까
Yeah, tell me about it.
오늘 멋지십니다
You look good, ma'am.
- 응 고마워, 조나
- 진짜로 진짜 멋지셔요
- Oh, thanks, Jonah.
- You look really good.
- Thank you.
- Yes, ma'am.
- 고맙다고
- 네, 부통령 님
이거 봤어?
Have you guys seen this?
케익 커팅식이 열리고
손님들이 축하 노래를 불렀지만
"When the cake was cut and the
guests sang 'Happy Birthday, '
어디에서도 부통령의 모습은
보이지 않았다
the VP was nowhere
to be seen."
내가 앤드류랑
대판 싸우고
They're saying I had
some sort of huge fight
우리 둘 사이는
순 허풍인 것처럼 써 놨네
with Andrew and that
our relationship is a sham.
못돼 빠진 것들
다이애나 비 때부터 알아 봤어
Monsters. It's like first
Princess Diana, now this.
애초부터 두 분이서
They think that at the
beginning of the night
카메라 앞에서
작정하고 쇼한 줄 아나 봐요
you and Andrew were playing
it up to the cameras.
얘네 '거짓말쟁이 설리나'
지랄하는 거 또 시작했어
And they're using this Meyer
the Liar bullshit again.
마이크, 대체 누구 소행일까?
Hey, Mike, who dug that up?
글쎄요, 어느 웬수가
안 까먹고 있다가
I don't know. Probably just
some idiot remembered it
삘 꽂혀서는
다시 물고 늘어지는 거겠죠
and then all of a sudden
it got traction.
'HuffPo'에 실린 내용입니다
And this is
from "HuffPo."
'랜달 하워드의 기대하시라'인데
Randall Howard's
forthcoming book
claims your relationship with Andrew
during the presidential campaign
대선 기간 동안의
두 분 사이는 순전히
유권자들을 사로잡기 위한
생쇼에 불과했다고 하는군요
was a lie invented by you
to mislead voters.
그 소리야말로 거짓말 아냐?
That's a lie, right?
- 맞습니다
- 아, 물론 사실이지
- Yeah.
- I mean, it's true
실제로 쇼한 거니까
그치만 켄트 아이디어라고
and it's what happened,
but it's Kent's lie.
내가 연출한 건 아니지
- It's not my lie.
- Right.
'거짓말쟁이 설리나'에 대해서
말들이 아주 많습니다
Meyer the Liar
has huge mo right now.
다들 그러잖아요
입에 착착 감기면 장땡이라고
You know, as people say,
if it rhymes, it chimes.
누가 그래?
난 첨 듣는데?
Who says that?
No one says that.
바람결에 들은 것 같습니다
I'm pretty sure
I heard someone say that.
이야기에 살이
붙고 있어요
Well, it's becoming
a narrative right now.
뭐라냐면 부통령 님께서
일전에 진실을 숨겼으니
And the narrative is
that you faked it before,
제 버릇 개 못 줬을 거라네요
so you must be faking it now.
설상가상이군
이요르 납셨다
Oh, great.
Here's Eeyore.
회동도 붐
파티도 붐
Deal, boom.
Party, boom.
붐붐통령이 아니시면
뭐란 말입니까
You are the boom boom veep.
Well, Catherine didn't appreciate the
fiscal party crashers last night.
캐서린은 어제의 재정 훌리건이
전혀 맘에 들지 않았나 봐
앤디랑 이따 밤에
딸애 데리고 외식할 예정이야
Andy and I have to take her
out to dinner tonight
어제 일도 있고 해서
to make up for the party
last night, so...
여러 사람 입에
오르내릴 겁니다
Okay, it'll be in public.
그러니 지지고 볶든 어쩌든
보여주기 식으로 비치면 안 됩니다
So whatever you do, don't
look like you're faking it
'거짓말쟁이 설리나'는 좆같은
초대형 참사의 전조에 불과하니까요
because this Meyer the Liar thing is
just an avalanche of shit right now.
그러니까 말이야
안 그래도 허덕이는 중이야
Yeah, tell me about it.
And I'm swimming in it
겨우 숨쉬는 와중이라고
and I'm breathing it in
through my snorkel.
성명을 하나 발표하세요
You need to issue
a statement, okay?
사생활은 어디까지나
사생활일 뿐이다
- My private life is private.
- Yes.
게다가 앤드류와 나는
전혀 앙숙이 아니다 하면서
Besides, Andrew and I,
we get along just fine.
요상한 게 뭐냐면, 벤
Ironically, Ben,
실제로 우린 아주 잘 지내
we actually are getting
along just fine.
방금 거 좋았어요
감쪽같으셨다고요
That's great.
That's a great fake.
척하는 거 아냐
사실이 그렇다니까
No, it's not a fake.
That's a real thing.
아, 다행이네요
그렇게 알리세요
Oh. Well, great.
Say that.
정말 미안해
I'm so sorry.
어제 파티가 돌연
경제 정상 회담이 됐었지
That party last night
turned into an economic summit.
그치만 얘야
지금 이렇게 다시 모였잖니
But you know what?
Here we are now for you.
- 생일 축하한다
- 당신도 축하해
- Happy birthday.
- And to you,
상어떼를 가로지르고
수영할 수 있겠네
a man who swims with sharks.
- 이젠 프리다이빙도 해
- 그게 뭐더라?
- Also starting free diving.
- Really? What is that?
무호흡으로 버틴다는 그거?
Is that when you try and hold your
breath for as long as possible?
추수감사절 때 어머니 곁에
찰싹 붙어있는 거랑 비슷해
Kind of like sitting next to my
mother after Thanksgiving dinner.
엄마, 또 가짜 웃음 터지셨네요
Mom, you're doing
your fake laugh again.
- 뭐라고?
- 왜 그러니, 재밌잖아
- What?
- Come on, this is nice.
아빠 눈엔 그닥
가짜같지 않은데
I can't tell if it's fake.
가짜인지 어떤지
절대로 못 알아차릴걸
You could never tell
if it was fake.
아니, 알아볼 수 있어
Yes, I could.
관심법이라도 쓰나 보지
Mm-hmm. What are you,
some sort of expert?
어떤 면에서는
In certain areas.
- 도대체 뭣들 하세요?
- 추근덕대는 거지
- What is going on right now?
- This is flirting.
너희 엄마 전문 아니겠니
Your mother
is an excellent flirt.
잘 보고 받아 적어 놔
You should take flirting notes.
그런 거 아니잖아요
This is not flirting.
페이스북에 누드사진 올리는
것만큼이나 불가사의한걸요
This is like as subtle as putting
a nude photo on Facebook.
보스턴 출신의 날
부통령 님께서 알아봐 주실까
Do you think Selina would
notice the invisible man
팩맨 코스튬이라도
좀 걸치면 낫겠지?
from the Boston PAC office
if I showed up at the office
in a Pac-Man costume?
그러니까 말야
미안하게 생각해
I know, I'm sorry.
잠깐만, 뭐가 미안한데?
I'm sorry,
why are you sorry?
글쎄
I don't know.
앓는 소리를 들은 것 같아서
사과할 타이밍인 줄 알았지
I heard whining and I assumed
I needed to apologize.
언제부터 딴 데
정신 팔려 있었어?
How long have you
not been listening to me?
상황을 예의 주시해야
한단 말이야
I just really need to
watch this because Andrew
앤드류는 휴화산이나
다름없거든
is like a dormant volcano
언제 뻥하고 터질지 몰라
and he can just blow
at any second.
난 가리비로 할게
I think I'm gonna
have the scallops.
- 나는 오늘....
- 뭐 시킬지 알아
- I think I'm gonna have--
- I know what you're gonna have.
- 당신 방금 이ㄱㅓ
- 하지 마
- You are going to have--
- Don't do that.
그 손 내려 놔
- Hmm?
- Put your hand down.
사내입네 하고 설치는 꼴
못 봐주겠으니까
I can't stand that
alpha male arrogant thing.
진짜 못 견디겠어, 앤드류
I really can't
stand it, Andrew.
설치는 건 아녔어
Okay, it's not arrogant.
그리 생각해 주다니
시발 엿같네
And fuck you for thinking so.
부디 용서해 줘
알아맞히면 재밌을 줄 알았지
Forgive me, I was just
anticipating your order.
- 뭘 예상했기에?
- 양고기 커틀릿
- Which was?
- Lamb cutlets.
아닌데
No.
맞잖아
족집게 같아서 미안하다
Yeah. I'm sorry
I know you, Selina.
사과할게
당신은 빤한 여자거든
Forgive me. You're not
a big mystery to me.
예의 그 억지 미소를
띄우다니 보기 좋다
And I'm very much enjoying
the plastered-on smile,
만사 괜찮은 척해야지
보는 눈들이 많으니까
pretending everything's okay
because people are watching.
개새짓 그만 해, 앤드류
Don't be a bastard, Andrew.
너도 웃으라고
You've got to do the same face.
너도 마찬가지야
옳지 잘한다
You put it on, too.
There we go.
추근덕대는 거라 하시더니
점점 더 미궁 속으로 빠지네요
Okay, well, now this flirting
is a little bit more subtle.
So, Ed.
Eddie.
저기, 에드
에디?
레이 맥캐스킬이랑
아는 사이예요?
Who do you know?
Do you know Ray McCaskill?
좋은 녀석이죠
Yeah, he's a great guy.
우리 둘 다 80년대
버디 영화 광팬이에요
We both are really into
'80s buddy comedies,
재밌게도 그러다 보니
둘이 찰떡궁합이 됐죠
which is ironically
how we became buddies.
찰떡궁합하고 자빠졌네
Fuck buddies.
조나, 여긴 왜 따라왔어?
Jonah, why are you here?
별 볼일도 없으면서?
You really don't have
anything to do, do you?
- 무시하면 되는데
- 누구를 말이야?
- Look, ignore him.
- Ignore who?
저 여자 보이지
부통령 님 도촬 중인데
Hey, I think that lady right there
just took a photo of Selina.
저 여자요?
This one?
두 분이 애증 관계란 건
저도 알아요
I understand that you guys
have a love-hate relationship,
그치만 정상적인 사람이라면
양극단을 오가게 마련이라고요
but most people
alternate emotions.
애증을 동시에
느끼진 않아요
They don't experience them
at the same time.
엄마랑 아빠는 늘
변덕스럽게 굴곤 했잖니
We've always had
a volatile relationship.
거지발싸개같은 관계
말씀이시죠
By that you mean
bat shit crazy.
- Passion was always an integral part.
- Yeah.
열정 빼면 시체라 할 수 있지
물론 싸우기도 했지
그것도 지긋지긋하게
Yes, there was fights.
Long, hard fights.
그치만 못잖게 지긋지긋한...
화해의 장도 빠지지 않았지?
Followed by long, hard...
making up, right?
두분이서 당장에라도
섹스하실 것 같은 촉이 오네요
Okay, I feel like you're
actually going to have sex
그거야말로 제 생일을 망치기에
무지막지하게 적합하겠군요
on this table and that would
truly ruin my birthday.
캐서린, 얘야
누가 레스토랑에서 섹스를 하니
Catherine, please. Nobody's
having sex on the table.
물론 우리 모두는
성적인 존재이지
- I mean, we are sexual beings, of course.
- Oh, my God.
실제로 섹스를 주고받던
사이기도 하고
We had sex.
We, you know--
- 것도 환상적으로
- 환상적인 섹스
- I mean, great sex.
- Great sex.
제 상담사한테
연락 좀 해야겠어요
Well, I'm going to have
to text my therapist.
금주는 또 뭔데?
What's the whole
not drinking thing?
- 퀘이커 신자거든요
- 뭣이?
- I'm a Quaker.
- What?
개풀 뜯어먹네
시발 그런 게 어딨어
Bullshit.
No one's a fucking Quaker.
말짱한 정신상태를 통해서만
인생의 우위를 선점하는 줄 알지
You probably think that staying sober
keeps you on top of your game.
Well, guess what. I work
hard and I play hard, bitch.
근데 있잖냐, 이 몸은
존나게 일하고 존나게 논다고
그게 바로 내 신조다
That's my credo.
내 존슨에도 그렇게 새겨뒀어
앞으로도 새길 공간은 남아돌지
I got that shit tattooed on
my dick with room to spare.
조나, 너 인간이 되다 말았구나
Jonah, you're not even a man.
인류의 축에도 못 껴
You're like an early
draft of a man
떡대만 과장되게 갈겨 놓은
스케치 단계의 인류랄까
where they just sketched out
a giant mangled skeleton,
조물주께서 미처
완성시키지 못했구나
but they didn't have time
to add details
채색이랄까 자존감은
찾아볼 수가 없어
like pigment
or self-respect.
프랑켄슈타인의 프랑켄슈타인이야
You're Frankenstein's monster
고자의 성기들을
재활용해서 만든 괴물
if his monster was made
entirely of dead dicks.
화장실 좀 다녀올게요
I'm gonna go to the bathroom.
안 하고 참아 보도록 하세요
Just try not to embarrass
yourselves while I'm gone.
애써 볼게
We'll give it a shot.
이렇게 마주하다니 기뻐
Nice to see you.
죄송합니다만
Um, I'm sorry.
- 잠시 한 말씀 올려도?
- 안 돼
- Can I interrupt a second?
- Uh, no.
이목이 집중돼 있습니다
다들 트위터며 도촬이며
It just looks like there's a
lot of people who are tweeting
바빠 보이는군요
처신하심에 있어 염두에 두시길
and taking pictures, so you
might want to be gesture-aware.
고마워, 괜찮으니 가 봐
It's fine. Thank you.
You can go.
- 알았대도?
- 네, 알겠습니다
- Okay?
- Yeah, okay.
할 말이 있어
I want to tell you something.
뭔데?
What?
회사 홍보 담당이
귀띔하기를
Um, the head of PR
우리 회사 명의로
후원을 했다나 봐
told me that our company
funded super PACs
지난 선거 때에
양당 모두에게
on both sides
during the last election.
되로 먹이는 것도 모자라서
I just was fluffed
말로 갖다 먹이는구나
and then I got fucked.
당최 믿을 수가 있어야지
I cannot believe
what you are telling me.
그거 알아?
웃어
Do you know-- smile.
쳐웃으라고, 병신아
활짝
Smile, you stupid asshole.
Make it bigger.
옳지, 그렇게
There you go.
언론이 날 못 잡아먹어서
얼마나 안달인지 알기나 해?
Do you have any idea how the
press is all over me right now?
이 사실을 어떻게
써갈길 것 같아?
And how they are gonna run
with the story
반대 진영에
자금을 대다니
about me funding my opponent?
이런 멍청한 개새끼를 보았나
You're a stupid fucking prick.
동의하지?
말해 봐
Right?
You say it.
동의할 수 없는데
I'm not gonna say that.
무슨 일 있었어요?
Okay, what happened now?
이젠 아예 나이프 들고
쑤실 것처럼 보이신다고요
You guys look like you're going to
stab each other with steak knives.
언쟁이 좀 있었단다
물론 웃음을 잃지 말아야지
We're having a fight
and we are smiling
가면을 쓰는 거야
너도 하렴, 오옳지
and putting a face on and you
can do that, too. There you go.
설리나, 일이니까 어쩌겠어
Selina, this is just business.
어떻게든 승자의 편에
서야 한다고
We want to end up
with the winner at the end.
사적인 감정에
휘둘렸던 건 아냐
There's nothing personal
about it, I promise.
당시엔 알지도 못했다고
I didn't even know about it.
오홓ㅎ, 뚫린 입이라고
Oh, that's utter bullshit.
그치만 말야?
정신줄 꼭 붙들려고
But you know what?
I'm keeping it together.
진짜야
난 멀쩡해
I really am.
It's all good.
- 만면에 미소를
- 미소를, 그렇고 말고
- We can keep smiling.
- Keep smiling. Yeah.
계속 그렇게들
억지 웃음 지으시면
I think that if you guys
continue to smile,
구안와사라도 오겠네요
you're actually gonna get
permanent lockjaw.
말도 재밌게 잘하네
She's so funny.
- 그렇지?
- 해학이 넘쳐
- Isn't she?
- Sarcastic.
잠시 실례하겠습니다
켄트 전략관 전화왔어요
I'm sorry to interrupt.
I just had a call from Kent.
조율안 좀 성사시켰기로서니
축하 인사했나 보네
Oh, to congratulate me 'cause
I made the deal last night.
- 전 국민들의 경사지
- 천만에
- America thanks you.
- You're welcome.
대통령께서 승인을
유보하시겠답니다
POTUS is going to stall
on that deal.
No, no, no. Why would he want to do that?
That can't be right.
아니, 왜 그러신대?
그럴 리가 없는데
정부 폐쇄 쪽으로
마음이 기우신 것 같답니다
Well, it sounds to me like he
wants a government shutdown
의회로 책임전가를 하는 한편
스파이 건을 잠재울 요량으로요
so he can blame it on Congress and
take the heat out of the spy story.
- Did you hear that?
- Yeah.
- 들었어?
- 그럼
시발통령 같으니, 그치?
이 시발 켄트
Fuck POTUS. Right?
And fuck Kent.
이런 시발
시발놈들 천지야
They're just
a bunch of fuckers.
고정하세요, 제발
- Uh-oh.
- No, no, no.
다 들렸을까?
나 폭발한 거?
Did they just get that?
Me being angry?
- 들렸을걸
- 당신한테 화낸 건 아니잖아
- Oh, yeah.
- But I wasn't being angry with you.
좀 전에 화내긴 했지만서도
I mean, I was angry
with you before,
지금은 당신 때문이 아니라고
but I'm not angry with you now.
- 아무렴 이해하지, 허니
- 허니로 슬슬 시동걸지 마
- I understand that, honey.
- Don't call me honey for starters.
정말이지 진정하세요
실성한 것 같아요
You have to calm down.
You look crazed.
- 저 여자 폰 좀 압수해 올래
- 저도 그러고 싶죠
- Can we confiscate that phone, please?
- I wish we could.
- 이미 늦었을걸요
- 잠시만요
- I think it's too late.
- Excuse me.
다투시는 사진이
트위터에 떴습니다
There's a picture on Twitter and it
looks like you guys are fighting.
- 뭣이? 저 여자지?
- 맞네요
- What? From that?
- Yes.
이것 좀 봐
말도 안 되지 않아?
Look at this. Look.
This is not what it is.
대통령 때문에 빡쳤는데
당신한테 삿대질 중이잖아
I'm pointing to you
because I'm mad about POTUS.
당신 때문에 돌겠다고
하던 중이 아니었는데
I wasn't saying that I was
angry to you about you.
알고 있어
일 더 크게 만들지 마
Okay, Lee, you're just
making it worse.
내가 아니라
저것들이 악화시키잖아
I'm not making it worse.
They're making it worse.
- 아빠, 손 거두세요
- 손모가지 날려야 정신차릴래?
- Dad, don't do that thing.
- Would you just cut that out?
Everybody sing.
축하의 노래를 부릅시다
아니, 아니야
이만 가봐야겠어
Nope, nope, nope.
We have to go.
- 넵, 넵
- 촛불 끄거라, 얘야
- Okay. Okay.
- Blow out your candles, honey.
- 다 무슨 소용이죠?
- 그래, 에미가 하마
- What's the point?
- Okay, I'll do it.
- 소원 빌어
- 다 됐다
- Make a wish.
- There, it's out.
소원은 차에서 마저 빌어
You can make your wish
in the car.
- 됐습니다요
- 내 물건 빠뜨리지 말고
- All right. All right.
- Get all my stuff.
물론입죠, 다 챙겼습니다
Oh, no, that's fine.
I'll get your stuff.
물렀거라
생일 축하 나가신다
Okay, happy birthday.
이제야 살 것 같네
This is good here.
여기서 내립니다
I'll get out.
뭐? 여기서?
What?
You're getting out here?
- 응
- 무슨 소리야?
- Yep.
- What are you talking about?
- 가야겠어
- 잠깐만
- I've got to go.
- Wait a minute.
기다려, 앤드류
얘기 좀 하자
Wait. Andrew, wait.
Wait. We need to talk.
잘 가렴, 아가
생일 축하한다
Bye, honey.
Happy birthday.
- 뭐하세요?
- 아오, 미치겠네
- Wait, what?
- God damn it.
뭘 어쩌잔 건데
도망치면 다야?
What are you doing
running away?
- 믿기지가 않는다
- 이리와 봐
- I cannot believe you.
- Come here.
- 망측해라, 뭐 하는 짓이야?
- 얼른 와 보래도
- Oh, my God, what are you doing?
- Come here right now.
왜 이러실까, 오훟
What are you doing? Oh!
하나님 맙소사
Oh, my God.
저기, 캐서린
Hey, Catherine.
케이크 참 좋아 보이는구나
Pretty nice cake you got there.
혼자 다 먹을 수 있겠어?
You gonna eat all of it?
좀 드실래요?
Do you want a piece?
- 응
- 케이크 먹고 싶으세요?
- I do.
- You want a piece of the cake?
지져스 이럴 수가 있구나
받으세요
Jesus fucking Christ.
Here.
여기요
Take that.
케익하면 당근 케익이지
Carrot cake's good.
- 넌 안 먹고?
- 네
- You want to try it?
- Nope.
다 드세요
It's all yours.
아저씨 폰으로
자를 수 있는데
I can use my phone to cut it.
한글자막 D (13myowncut@gmail.com)